<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<codeBook xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="ddi:codebook:2_5" version="2.5" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" xml:lang="en">
  <docDscr>
    <citation>
      <titlStmt>
        <titl>DDI description: Study on Streamlining the Use of Education and Training Data: Data Producers' Survey 2023</titl>
        <parTitl xml:lang="fi">DDI-kuvailu: Kasvatus- ja koulutustietojen hyödyntämisen sujuvoittamisselvitys: tiedontuottajien kysely 2023</parTitl>
        <IDNo agency="FSD">3892</IDNo>
      </titlStmt>
      <prodStmt>
        <producer abbr="FSD">Finnish Social Science Data Archive</producer>
        <copyright>Finnish Social Science Data Archive</copyright>
        <prodPlac>Finnish Social Science Data Archive</prodPlac>
      </prodStmt>
      <verStmt>
        <version date="2024-12-18" type="mef_eng">1.0.0</version>
      </verStmt>
      <biblCit>Study on Streamlining the Use of Education and Training Data: Data Producers' Survey 2023 [metadata]. Metadata version 1.0.0 (2024-12-18). Finnish Social Science Data Archive [producer and distributor]. DOI: https://doi.org/10.60686/t-fsd3892; URN: https://urn.fi/urn:nbn:fi:fsd:T-FSD3892</biblCit>
      <holdings location="Finnish Social Science Data Archive FSD" URI="https://urn.fi/urn:nbn:fi:fsd:T-FSD3892" />
    </citation>
    <notes xml:lang="fi">FSD:n aineistokuvailut (FSD metadata records), joiden tekijä on Suomen yhteiskuntatieteellinen tietoarkisto (Finnish Social Science Data Archive), on lisensoitu Creative Commons 1.0 Yleismaailmallinen (CC0 1.0) -lisenssillä.
      <ExtLink URI="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.fi" />
    </notes>
    <notes xml:lang="en">FSD:n aineistokuvailut (FSD metadata records) by Suomen yhteiskuntatieteellinen tietoarkisto (Finnish Social Science Data Archive) are licensed under a Creative Commons 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) license.
      <ExtLink URI="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.en" />
    </notes>
    <notes xml:lang="sv">FSD:n aineistokuvailut (FSD metadata records) av Finlands samhällsvetenskapliga dataarkiv (Finnish Social Science Data Archive) är licensierade under en Creative Commons 1.0 Universiell (CC0 1.0) licens.
      <ExtLink URI="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/deed.sv" />
    </notes>
  </docDscr>
  <stdyDscr>
    <citation>
      <titlStmt>
        <titl>Study on Streamlining the Use of Education and Training Data: Data Producers' Survey 2023</titl>
        <parTitl xml:lang="fi">Kasvatus- ja koulutustietojen hyödyntämisen sujuvoittamisselvitys: tiedontuottajien kysely 2023</parTitl>
        <IDNo agency="FSD">3892</IDNo>
        <IDNo agency="URN">urn:nbn:fi:fsd:T-FSD3892</IDNo>
        <IDNo agency="DOI">10.60686/t-fsd3892</IDNo>
      </titlStmt>
      <rspStmt>
        <AuthEnty affiliation="Tampere University">Kauko, Jaakko
          <ExtLink URI="https://orcid.org/0000-0003-0538-6806" role="PID" title="orcid">0000-0003-0538-6806</ExtLink>
        </AuthEnty>
      </rspStmt>
      <prodStmt>
        <producer>Ministry of Education and Culture</producer>
        <copyright>In accordance with the agreement between FSD and the depositor.</copyright>
        <grantNo agency="Ministry of Education and Culture">OKM016:00/2023</grantNo>
      </prodStmt>
      <distStmt>
        <distrbtr abbr="FSD" URI="https://www.fsd.tuni.fi/">Finnish Social Science Data Archive</distrbtr>
        <distDate date="2024-12-20" />
      </distStmt>
      <serStmt ID="S8" URI="https://services.fsd.tuni.fi/catalogue/series/8?lang=en">
        <serName>Individual datasets</serName>
        <serInfo>
          <p>Individual datasets that do not belong to any series.</p>
        </serInfo>
      </serStmt>
      <verStmt>
        <version date="2024-11-25" type="main_data">1.0</version>
      </verStmt>
      <biblCit>Kauko, Jaakko (Tampere University): Study on Streamlining the Use of Education and Training Data: Data Producers' Survey 2023 [dataset]. Data version 1.0 (2024-11-25). Finnish Social Science Data Archive [distributor]. DOI: https://doi.org/10.60686/t-fsd3892; URN: https://urn.fi/urn:nbn:fi:fsd:T-FSD3892</biblCit>
      <holdings location="Finnish Social Science Data Archive FSD" URI="https://urn.fi/urn:nbn:fi:fsd:T-FSD3892" />
    </citation>
    <stdyInfo>
      <subject>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">education</keyword>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">educational institutions</keyword>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">adult education institutions</keyword>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">educational associations</keyword>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">information users</keyword>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">right to information</keyword>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">data transmission</keyword>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">information services</keyword>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">data privacy</keyword>
        <keyword vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="https://elsst.cessda.eu/id">data protection</keyword>
        <topcClas vocab="OKM" vocabURI="http://www.yso.fi/onto/okm-tieteenala/conceptscheme">Social sciences</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="OKM" vocabURI="http://www.yso.fi/onto/okm-tieteenala/conceptscheme">Other</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="CESSDA Topic Classification" vocabURI="https://vocabularies.cessda.eu/urn/urn:ddi:int.cessda.cv:TopicClassification:4.2.3">Information society</topcClas>
        <topcClas vocab="CESSDA Topic Classification" vocabURI="https://vocabularies.cessda.eu/urn/urn:ddi:int.cessda.cv:TopicClassification:4.2.3">Education</topcClas>
      </subject>
      <abstract>
        <p>The survey examines how Finnish education and training providers manage and share the information they possess, as well as the challenges they encounter in these processes. The survey targeted early childhood education and care institutions, primary and secondary education institutions, liberal education providers, and other training organizations. The data was collected as part of a Ministry of Education and Culture project aimed at streamlining the use of educational information.</p>
        <p>The first theme of the survey focused on how information is recorded and managed in the organisation of education and training. Respondents were asked what information their organisation internally stores for organising education or training, as well as for other purposes. They were also asked about the challenges encountered in data storage, the basis for their organisation's data processing practices, and where they can seek help if data processing issues arise.</p>
        <p>The next section focused on data use. Respondents were asked whether they use the data produced by their organisation for any purpose other than what it was originally collected for. Respondents were also asked which education and training data they use, for what purposes and under what regulation. They were also asked about challenges encountered in using data within their organisation and whether the data they produce is shared with other actors. Finally, respondents were asked if their organisation uses data recorded or produced by other actors and whether there are any problems encountered in obtaining the information.</p>
        <p>Background information included the language of the response and the name and region of the organisation represented by the respondent. The data were organised into an easy to use HTML version at FSD.</p>
      </abstract>
      <sumDscr>
        <timePrd event="single" date="2023" />
        <collDate event="start" date="2023-05-29" />
        <collDate event="end" date="2023-11-03" />
        <nation abbr="FI">Finland</nation>
        <geogCover>Finland</geogCover>
        <anlyUnit>Organization/Institution
          <concept vocab="DDI Analysis Unit" vocabURI="https://vocabularies.cessda.eu/urn/urn:ddi:int.ddi.cv:AnalysisUnit:2.1.3">OrganizationOrInstitution</concept>
        </anlyUnit>
        <anlyUnit>Event/Process/Activity
          <concept vocab="DDI Analysis Unit" vocabURI="https://vocabularies.cessda.eu/urn/urn:ddi:int.ddi.cv:AnalysisUnit:2.1.3">EventOrProcessOrActivity</concept>
        </anlyUnit>
        <universe clusion="I">Education and training providers, educational institutions and their representative national organisations in primary and secondary level and in liberal adult education in Finland</universe>
        <universe clusion="E">the Åland Islands</universe>
        <dataKind>Qualitative</dataKind>
      </sumDscr>
    </stdyInfo>
    <method>
      <dataColl>
        <timeMeth>Cross-section
          <concept vocab="DDI Time Method" vocabURI="https://vocabularies.cessda.eu/urn/urn:ddi:int.ddi.cv:TimeMethod:1.2.3">CrossSection</concept>
        </timeMeth>
        <dataCollector affiliation="Tampere University">Kauko, Jaakko</dataCollector>
        <sampProc>Non-probability: Purposive
          <concept vocab="DDI Sampling Procedure" vocabURI="https://vocabularies.cessda.eu/urn/urn:ddi:int.ddi.cv:SamplingProcedure:2.0.2">Nonprobability.Purposive</concept>
        </sampProc>
        <sampProc>
          <p>For national organisations and central organisations, the sample included the largest actors in the sector, of which eight responded. In addition, there was one regional or national actor in the private early childhood education sector among the respondents. The main providers of education and training are municipalities, of which nine municipalities with the largest population were included. Of the remaining 300 municipalities, ten were included: one municipality from each population decile. For the sample, municipalities were balanced according to statistical grouping of municipalities, region and linguistic diversity. For the selection of schools and kindergartens, a second sample was selected with the same diversity factors as for the selection of municipalities. For primary and secondary education, liberal adult education and early childhood education diversity was sought by including special education schools. In addition to municipalities, education can be provided by private operators, the State or a consortium of education and training associations.</p>
          <p>The link to the Webropol platform was sent by the Ministry of Education and Culture to the 49 operators in the sample with a cover letter. Some respondents were contacted individually by e-mail or telephone to encourage them to respond. A total of 32 responses were received, with a response rate of 64%. The addresses of the national actors and municipalities were found in the databases of the Ministry of Education and Culture, while the addresses of other actors were obtained from public sources. In the municipalities, the questionnaire was sent via the registry offices, which caused variations in who finally received the questionnaire in their e-mail. The sample was increased by one because in one case the link had gone all the way to the educational institution, even though the municipality was the intended respondent.</p>
        </sampProc>
        <collMode>Self-administered questionnaire: Web-based (CAWI)
          <concept vocab="DDI Mode of Collection" vocabURI="https://vocabularies.cessda.eu/urn/urn:ddi:int.ddi.cv:ModeOfCollection:5.0.1">SelfAdministeredQuestionnaire.CAWI</concept>
        </collMode>
        <resInstru>Unstructured questionnaire
          <concept vocab="DDI Type of Instrument" vocabURI="https://vocabularies.cessda.eu/urn/urn:ddi:int.ddi.cv:TypeOfInstrument:1.1.2">Questionnaire.Unstructured</concept>
        </resInstru>
      </dataColl>
      <anlyInfo>
        <dataAppr>The most significant lack of coverage is that only one kindergarten responded to the survey. In terms of geographical coverage of municipalities, three provinces were not represented.</dataAppr>
      </anlyInfo>
      <stdyClas type="A">Detailed and specific data description in Finnish and English. The data are checked and processed in detail. If necessary, the data are anonymised.</stdyClas>
    </method>
    <dataAccs>
      <setAvail>
        <accsPlac URI="https://www.fsd.tuni.fi/">Finnish Social Science Data Archive</accsPlac>
        <collSize>21 files in txt format. Additionally, the data were organised into an easy to use HTML version and a CSV version.</collSize>
        <complete>The original dataset consisted of 32 responses, of which 21 were archived in the FSD. 11 responses are missing from the archived data because permission for their archiving was not obtained. If a respondent did not answer a particular question, a dash (-) has been marked in the corresponding field.</complete>
      </setAvail>
      <useStmt>
        <restrctn>The dataset is (A) openly available for all users without registration (CC BY 4.0).</restrctn>
        <citReq>The data and its creators shall be cited in all publications and presentations for which the data have been used. The bibliographic citation may be in the form suggested by the archive or in the form required by the publication.</citReq>
        <deposReq>Notify FSD of all publications where you have used the data by sending the citation information to user-services.fsd@tuni.fi.</deposReq>
        <disclaimer>The original data creators and the archive bear no responsibility for any results or interpretations arising from the reuse of the data.</disclaimer>
      </useStmt>
      <notes>For identification reasons, the researchers have removed all direct identifiers, names of cities and municipalities and information identifying organisations from the data. They have also removed all sections of the data that were promised only for the use of the research team. The changes made to the open-ended responses are indicated by [square brackets]. The order of respondents has also been randomized after anonymization.</notes>
    </dataAccs>
    <othrStdyMat>
      <relMat>Kauko, Jaakko; Penttinen, Jaakko; Rötsä, Maarit; Voutilainen, Tomi (2024). Sujuva kasvatus- ja koulutustietojen hyödyntäminen : Selvitysryhmän loppuraportti. Opetus- ja kulttuuriministeriön julkaisuja 2024:17 Opetus- ja kulttuuriministeriö.
        <ExtLink URI="http://urn.fi/URN:ISBN:978-952-263-926-4" />
      </relMat>
      <relPubl xml:lang="fi">Kauko, Jaakko; Penttinen, Jaakko; Rötsä, Maarit; Voutilainen, Tomi (2024). Sujuva kasvatus- ja koulutustietojen hyödyntäminen : Selvitysryhmän loppuraportti. Opetus- ja kulttuuriministeriön julkaisuja 2024:17 Opetus- ja kulttuuriministeriö. http://urn.fi/URN:ISBN:978-952-263-926-4
        <citation>
          <titlStmt>
            <titl>Sujuva kasvatus- ja koulutustietojen hyödyntäminen : Selvitysryhmän loppuraportti</titl>
            <IDNo agency="URN">URN:ISBN:978-952-263-926-4</IDNo>
          </titlStmt>
          <distStmt>
            <distDate date="2024" />
          </distStmt>
          <holdings URI="http://urn.fi/URN:ISBN:978-952-263-926-4" />
        </citation>
      </relPubl>
    </othrStdyMat>
  </stdyDscr>
</codeBook>
